

# TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Python Python Scientific Stack SQL Tableau R

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Statistics
Machine Learning
Predictive Analytics
Data Management
Business Intelligence
Enterprise Analysis
Big Data

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

Public speaking and presenting Creative problem solving Fast learner Organized Critical thinker Team player Motivated

## CONTACT

P: (425) 890-8664 E: adams.allisong@gmail.com W: adamsallisong.github.io

# ALLISON ADAMS

# DATA SCIENTIST

I am an experienced Data Scientist and enjoy tackling challenging problems by designing creative solutions. Skilled at distilling critical business information from large fields of data and visually presenting information in a compelling, digestible fashion.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **DATA SCIENTIST**

Syndio Solutions | July 2019 - Present

- Develop advanced descriptive and inferential people analytics statistical models (e.g., t-test, chi-square, correlation, multi-variate regression, optimization functions)
- Analyze and process complex data using advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools
- Draft technical documents and white papers summarizing research projects, including executive summaries for presentation to senior & executive leadership

#### **QA SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Brooks Sports | Nov 2016 - June 2019

- Lead test engineer developing data-driven selenium automated test framework reducing manual testing while reflecting real-world e-commerce complexities integrated with CI/CD programs
- Facilitate bug triage through JIRA in Agile workstreams
- Review business requirements driving discussions with developers and IT partners to develop go forward requirements

#### **SENIOR SYSTEMS ANALYST**

Liberty Mutual | Sept 2015 - Nov 2016

- Develop complex SQL Queries accessing both test and production databases providing dashboard KPI and statistical results
- Lead documentation and translation of high-level business workflows to techincal requirements for development team

## **IT ANALYST**

Liberty Mutual | May 2013 -Sept 2015

- Cultivate an understanding of the software development lifecycle, and how to institute innovation within a larger technology ecosystem
- Establish technical foundation skills and increasing communication abilities for presentations and cross-team collaboration

## **EDUCATION**

#### MASTER OF SCIENCE: MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEMS

Emphasis in Data Analytics, Machine Learning and Business Intelligence Seattle Pacific University | 2019

#### **BACHELOR OF ARTS, MAJOR IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION**

Emphasis in Management Information Systems Washington State University | 2013